Finding Aid for the Pamela Gearhart Collection of Photographs, 1946-1983
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Additional receipts, 1946-circa 1975, II.; Items 31-207
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting outside with a dog, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 113)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting outside with a dog, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 114)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting outside with a dog, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 115)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting outside with a dog, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 116)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting outside, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 117)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting outside, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 118)
  - Mrs. Buys standing outside a house on Delancey Street in Philadelphia, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 119)
    City: Philadelphia (Pa.)
  - Pamela Gearhart high school portrait, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 120)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart with violin, 1952, 1 color transparency; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 121)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart with violin, 1952, 1 color transparency; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 122)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart, head shot, 1952, 1 color transparency; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 123)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart, 1952, 1 color transparency; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 124)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart with violin, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: W. C. Runder Photo Co. (Saint Louis, Mo.) (Box 1, Item 125)
    City: Saint Louis (Mo.)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart with violin (close-up), undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 126)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart with violin, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 127)
  - Christmas card with photograph of Pamela Gearhart, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 128)
  - Christmas card with photograph of Russell Gerhart, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 129)
  - Pamela Gearhart standing in front of the USS Constitution in Boston, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 130)
    City: Boston (Mass.)
  - Pamela Gearhart standing in front of the USS Constitution in Boston, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 131)
  - Bill Flavia standing in front of the USS Constitution in Boston, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 132)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting on a bench with her mother Martha, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 133)
  - Pamela Gearhart standing outside with pianist Claudette Sorel, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 134)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting outside with pianist Claudette Sorel, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 135)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting in a boat with pianist Claudette Sorel and Russell Gerhart, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 136)
  - Russell Gerhart in boat with a child feeding ducks, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 137)
  - Russell and Martha Gerhart sitting in a boat at a dock, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 138)
  - Russell Gerhart sitting in a boat, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 139)
  - Martha Gerhart standing with Russell Gerhart in the background standing in a boat, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 140)
  - Pamela Gearhart fishing with her father Russell, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 141)
  - Pamela Gearhart fishing with her father Russell, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 142)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting in a boat, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 143)
  - Composer Howard Hanson (right), with conductor Edward Murphy and the Chautauqua Institution's Student Symphony Orchestra, with Pamela Gearhart, concertmistress, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 144)
  - Pamela Gearhart standing outside with her father Russell, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 145)
  - Pamela Gearhart standing outside with her father Russell and mother Martha, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 146)
  - Pamela Gearhart standing outside with two women, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 147)
  - Pamela Gearhart standing outside with a woman, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 148)
  - Portrait of John Batrus, circa 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 149)
  - Russell Gerhart in boat with a child feeding ducks, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 150)
  - Russell and Martha Gerhart sitting on the ground by a dock, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 151)
  - Violist Sally Trembly (looking at camera), cellist Ronald Leonard (center, rear), and violinist Michael Applebaum (Tree) at Curtis Institute of Music, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 152)
    Location: Curtis Institute of Music
  - Pianist Isabelle Vengerova and Mary Louise Curtis Bok Zimbalist on the entry stairs at Curtis Institute of Music, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 153)
  - Curtis Music Institute founder Mary Louise Curtis Bok Zimbalist (far right) on sidewalk in front of the school with her chauffeur Patrick holding the car door open for a woman, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 154)
  - Curtis Music Institute founder Mary Louise Curtis Bok Zimbalist (white hair) on sidewalk in front of the school with crowd after 1954 graduation ceremony, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 155)
  - Bassoonist Patsy Hayes, violinist Ann Garliches (far right), author Catherine Drinker Bowen (with corsage), and Mary Louise Curtis Bok Zimbalist (white hair) after 1954 graduation ceremony at Curtis Institute of Music, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 156)
  - Pianist Judy Jaimes and organist Vernon Wolcott (glasses) after 1954 graduation ceremony at Curtis Institute of Music, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 157)
  - Flutist Milton Burgy and Curtis Institute of Music receptionist Patsy Allan, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 158)
  - Bassoonist Patsy Hayes (leaning), Mary Louise Curtis Bok Zimbalist (white hair), and Curtis Institute of Music receptionist Patsy Allan after the 1954 graduation ceremony, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 159)
  - Pamela Gearhart standing with Philadelphia Museum of Art in background, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 160)
    Location: Philadelphia Museum of Art
  - View from Philadelphia Museum of Art down the Benjamin Franklin Parkway towards center Philadelphia, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 161)
  - Unidentified male standing in front of the Rodin Museum in Philadelphia, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 162)
    Location: Rodin Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
  - Unidentified male standing on the steps of the Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 163)
  - Unidentified male standing with Philadelphia Museum of Art in the background, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 164)
  - View from Philadelphia Museum of Art down the Benjamin Franklin Parkway towards center Philadelphia, 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 165)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart playing violin, December 29 1954, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Gouldthorpe (Box 1, Item 166)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart holding violin standing in front of a blackboard, circa 1957, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 167)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart playing violin, April 1960, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Wheelan Photograph Studio (Buffalo, N.Y.) (Box 1, Item 168)
  - Pamela Gearhart in concert dress talking with an unidentified woman, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 169)
  - Pamela Gearhart in concert dress talking with people, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 170)
  - Pamela Gearhart in concert dress talking with people, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 171)
  - Pamela Gearhart holding a piece of paper and a cup, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 172)
    Location: State University of New York at Buffalo
  - Pamela Gearhart holding music at a rehearsal of the State University of New York at Buffalo Orchestra, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 173)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the State University of New York at Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 174)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the State University of New York at Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 175)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the State University of New York at Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 176)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the State University of New York at Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 177)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the State University of New York at Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Buffalo Evening News (Box 1, Item 178)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 179)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 180)
  - Portrait of Pamela Gearhart, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 181)
  - Pamela Gearhart gesturing at an orchestra rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 182)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 183)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 184)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 185)
  - Pamela Gearhart gesturing at an orchestra rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 186)
  - Pamela Gearhart gesturing at an orchestra rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 187)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 188)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Tuttle, Jim, 1913-2006 (Box 1, Item 189)
  - Pamela Gearhart with her father Russell Gerhart, January 17 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 190)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the Community Music School of Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 191)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the Community Music School of Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 192)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the Community Music School of Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 193)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the Community Music School of Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 194)
  - Pamela Gearhart holding violin bow at a rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 195)
  - Pamela Gearhart gesturing during a rehearsal of wind players, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 196)
  - Pamela Gearhart gesturing at an orchestra rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 197)
  - Pamela Gearhart gesturing at a rehearsal of the Community Music School of Buffalo Orchestra, undated, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 198)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the Community Music School of Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 199)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the Community Music School of Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 200)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting the Community Music School of Buffalo Orchestra in rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Sinderbrand (Box 1, Item 201)
  - Pamela Gearhart standing with arms outstretched in front of a body of water, undated, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 202)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting a performance with audience members in the background, May 7 1974, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Stoddard, Robert E. (Box 1, Item 203)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting a performance with audience members in the background, May 7 1974, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Stoddard, Robert E. (Box 1, Item 204)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting a performance with audience members in the background, May 7 1974, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Stoddard, Robert E. (Box 1, Item 205)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting a performance with audience members in the background, May 7 1974, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Stoddard, Robert E. (Box 1, Item 206)
  - Pamela Gearhart conducting at an orchestra rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 207)
  - Pamela Gearhart sitting in a boat with pianist Claudette Sorel and Russell Gerhart, 1953, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 208)
  - Alexander Schneider eating outside with Pamela Gearhart, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Suárez, Thomas (Box 2, Item 209)
  - Pamela Gearhart at a rehearsal of the Baird Youth Chamber Players with Alexander Schneider in the background, 1966 August 10, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Suárez, Thomas (Box 2, Item 210)
  - Alexander Schneider playing violin at a rehearsal, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 2, Item 211)
  - Pamela Gearhart at a rehearsal of the Baird Youth Chamber Players with two unidentified men on stage, 1966 August 10, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Suárez, Thomas (Box 2, Item 212)
  - Alexander Schneider riding a bicycle, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Suárez, Thomas (Box 2, Item 213)
  - Drawing that attaches to bottom of photograph of Alexander Schneider riding a bicycle, undated, 1 ink drawing (Box 2, Item 214)
  - Jack Benny talking to Alexander Schneider at a rehearsal of the Baird Youth Chamber Players, 1966 August 10, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Suárez, Thomas (Box 2, Item 215)
  - Jack Benny standing next to Alexander Schneider at a rehearsal of the Baird Youth Chamber Players, 1966 August 10, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Suárez, Thomas (Box 2, Item 216)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Women conductors (Music)--New York (State)--Photographs; Women violinists--New York (State)--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs; Gearhart, Pamela--Photographs; Gerhart, Russell, 1902-1972--Photographs; Gerhart, Martha, 1901-1978--Photographs; Gearhart, Livingston--Photographs; Schneider, Alexander, 1908-1993--Photographs; Schneider, Mischa, 1903-1985--Photographs; Henderson, Skitch, 1918-2005--Photographs; Benny, Jack, 1894-1974--Photographs
Genres
Photographs
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Pamela Gearhart Papers, 1956-1993
Mus. Arc. 33
The Pamela Gearhart Papers contain a biographical summary, curriculum vitae, correspondence, newspaper clippings, and programs.
Livingston Gearhart Papers, 1933-1997
Mus. Arc. 23.1
The collection contains prose writings, vitae, correspondence, teaching materials, programs, and clippings.
Livingston Gearhart Recordings, 1949-2001
Mus. Arc. 23.4
The collection contains reel to reel and cassette tapes, compact discs, and LPs containing music composed or arranged by Livingston Gearhart.